I welcome back. So this is our first chapter, first section of our network. Let's start.
What is a computer? So this is the definition that you have to tell your interval,
if your interval asked, what is a computer? And you tell the same definition which is written over
here. I am 100% old, the interval never can be able to reach at you. If you tell this proper
definition to him or her, then he knows, or she knows that, yeah, this student, this particular person
knows what is computer. He is clear with his thoughts. So let's start with the definition.
At its core, a computer is an electronic machine. You can set device, designed to execute
a series of instructions. When we are calling about a series of instructions, it is a software,
when we run software, a series of instructions go through, which will run hardware, okay,
performing automatic or logical operations. Yeah, it is pamory function is to manipulate information
or data, meaning it can store a drive-to-brand process data with incredible speed and accuracy. Yeah, modern
digital electronic computers are highly versatile, okay, they can perform a generic set of operation
known as program. That's what I'm calling. This program tells the computer exactly what to do
enabling it to handle complex tasks from running your favorite app to powering vast global network.
Okay, so I hope you understand that what is the definition of a computer, what to, okay,
let's move ahead. How computer complicates, okay, so computer complicates Cassieck, how it
communicate actually, how one system is communicate with another system, how I am communicating
to my system. Yeah, so, human language versus computer language. So yeah, as we know that
computer does not know in the, in English, French, German and sector sector, he knows some specific
thing that on that works all over the world. Now, as AI is green, so English is the one of the
language that is used for communicate to machine. So here in a core of computer, bind is used,
which is a band, it is either one or either zero. Okay, computer complicates and understand
formation using special language called bandry, bandry consists of only two digits, one or zero,
in which zero means of one means true. You have to remember true, true case spelling of
two is t, r, u, e, t stand for one, okay, and then there is zero, zero, z, e, r, o, o, of, that's how I
remember when I was learning, not really. Now, here every, every word, either it's capital Y,
small y, capital E, how it is stored in a bandry format, you can see there, why it's stored in
this way, he's stored in this way, let's move here. What is s, t, the translator for computer,
the many of you pronounce it as a sky. Yeah, I also pronounce it like a sky, but it is s, g.
It's t stand for American standard code for information interchange, interchange, it's a
character encoding standard or computer used to represent text, SQL code a unique number to each
later, visit symbol, you see on your keyboard, so whatever the you see on the keyboard,
each have different as key, okay. Now, both, as you can see, there is an important thing, both
as key and bandry are case sensitive, yet definitely, as I told you, capital Y small y is different,
this means capital Y in a small y at created as completely different characteristic,
character by the computer, each having its own unique SK value and bandry representation,
you can see, how capital Y is in N, small y is 101, and it is represented in bandry equivalent
is totally different, where, wow, computer hardware, the tangible components, so what is hardware?
Hardware differs to physical components of a computer system, these are the parts you can see,
touch the tangible pieces that make up the machine, without hardware, software have nothing to run,
okay. So basically, the hardware is hardware, everything that you can teach is hardware,
your RAM, your data storage, it is SGD, SGD, graphic, your sound cards, your motherboard,
your CPU, okay. So this is the thing that you can learn and it is all basic, so you have,
you know, let's move it, computer software that intangible instruction, so software is the one
that we can touch, okay. So software refers to the set of programs, data instruction,
that guide the computer hardware to perform specific tasks, unlike hardware, software is
intangible, you can't touch it, but it's what makes the computer useful, definitely. Next,
the most crucial type of software is the operating system, Windows, Linux, operating system,
the OSIRO as the system software that fascinate a communication between you,
the end user, I am the end user, a human is the end user, okay, and the computer hardware.
So it was the one that makes a communication between the human and a machine,
was facilitate this, was make it more friendly, was allow you to interact with the computer
without needing to no complex machine in any language. It also enables the execution of
various software applications like Microsoft of his games calculator and much, much more over.
It also help computer resources such as memory and the CPU, and schedule tasks to ensure
everything runs smoothly. Now, here we are talking about like when we will run a specific type
of software, how much process, how much memory, how much or I have to put there, it is done
by CPU, OS, okay. So this type of thing next. Application software, okay, so there's my
there we talk about opening system, now we can talk about the software. So OS and it's the core
function of the computer, application software is what you use to perform specific tasks or activity,
if there was a bridge between you and the OS, along with you to interact with the hardware,
access where it is featured and functionality tailored to your needs. Yeah, so there's a kind of
software that is used to perform some functionality, some specific tasks that will make your
life easy. We have presentations of video and device, your security software, your web browser,
web processing software, games, blah, blah, blah, blah. Next. So oh yeah, so whatever the key
take place in this section we have, computers are very powerful machine, they talked using a
binary, but there is a SK that is wholesome values. Now, hardware is a software, what is a hardware
that we can test software, we can't able to test, open the system, buy it a session, because
it managed computer resources and allow us human being to interact with it easily. Application,
what do it enhance productivity, it provides some information that which
software takes, which amount of process and web browsing, browsers and what processing
present as a software that make our life much easy. Thank you for joining this introduction to
computer concept. We hope this, you must find that is still important for you. I hope you like it.
Next we go in much more deep. This is just a beginning, just a basic and yeah, this is all I
written by myself. And yeah, for presentation, I used gamma. So I hope I'm not sponsoring a sponsor
by gamma, but however I make the presentation with it, it's genuinely cool. Bye bye.